<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gsoc-2019 on Naveenaidu</title>
    <link>http://www.example.com/categories/gsoc-2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gsoc-2019 on Naveenaidu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 16:30:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.example.com/categories/gsoc-2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC: Handle Nested Languages Overview</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-final-phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 16:30:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-final-phase/</guid>
      <description>Hiya Everyone!!
This post will explain in brief about the work I had done during the Google Summer of Code 2019 with coala. For the unitiated, my project was to give coala the capability to handle nested programming language in a single file.
 The Official link to the project is here My Proposal for the project is here  I must say, there is a huge contrast between the project proposal I submitted and the actual implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC: Phase 1 Overview</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-phase-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 16:30:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-phase-1/</guid>
      <description>Hiya crawlers!
This post will cover my learnings of phase 1 of GSoC with coala. As I explained in my previous GSOC post about the 4 different phases of my project. For the uninitatied, the project for my GSoC is to add functionality into coala which would enable it into Linting files that have nested languages.
I divided my project into 4 phases:
 Information Gathering Segregating the nested file Linting the file Assembling  For the newbies here, I highly suggest that you read the previous blog about the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC: Handle Nested Languages Overview</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-overview-handle-nested-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 16:30:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-overview-handle-nested-languages/</guid>
      <description>Hola Amigos!
The Coding Phase - 1  of GSoC has started and it has been pretty fun. I also have my University Finals going on now. They&amp;rsquo;ll end on July 3rd. Banglore does live in a different kind of world :P - Phew! This is a really busy month. I have to manage Finals, GSoC and Open Mainframe Internship cocurrently. I like this kind of atmosphere though. It keeps me on my toes and pushes me to break my own boundaries and limits that I so absent mindedly set upon on myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC: Accepted Yaay!</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 16:30:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/gsoc-accepted/</guid>
      <description>Yaaay! I was accepted as the Google Summer of code student at coala. I have been waiting for this day for a long long time now (Almost a year).This can be counted as one of my first big achievement so far :)
The project I got accepted is Handling Nested Language. This project is about extending the functionality of coala to give it the support to run it&amp;rsquo;s analysis on files that contains nested languages (Multiple languages in one file ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Chapter</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/posts/a-new-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 16:30:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/posts/a-new-chapter/</guid>
      <description>Hola People!
It&amp;rsquo;s been raining since evening here. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a rainy person, I like the cold breeze that the rain bring with it. The feeling of the cold breeze rustling through my hair and my face rejuvenates me. In one word, it&amp;rsquo;s orgasmic. I do not have any pictures of today, But I&amp;rsquo;ll make sure to capture a few when the weather turns sexy again.
Anyway this post is about the New Adventure that I have embarked upon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>